<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://devopschampion.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://devopschampion.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Devops Champion</title><subtitle>Devops Champion - Beginning with Incident Response. Your systems are down! Customers are calling. Every moment counts. What do you do?</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Building On-call Rosters</title><link href="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Building-Oncall-Rosters.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building On-call Rosters" /><published>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Building-Oncall-Rosters</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Building-Oncall-Rosters.html">&lt;p&gt;Rosters establish a framework around who is on-call at any given point. A roster, or team, is made up of multiple engineers. Rosters can also contain multiple rotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/modules/incident-response-with-alerting-on-azure/&quot;&gt;MS Learn: Improve Incident Response with Alerting in Azure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-Building-Oncall-Rotations.html&quot;&gt;Building On-call Rotations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Rosters establish a framework around who is on-call at any given point. A roster, or team, is made up of multiple engineers. Rosters can also contain multiple rotations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Building On-call Rotations</title><link href="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Building-Oncall-Rotations.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Building On-call Rotations" /><published>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Building-Oncall-Rotations</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Building-Oncall-Rotations.html">&lt;p&gt;A rotation is a scheduled shift. Engineers takes the “on-call” responsibility for their own specific recurring rotation. There are several types of shifts that you can create – some more common than others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;24-x-7&quot;&gt;24 x 7&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is a rotation where engineers will be “on-call” for several days in a row. However, most “Elite/High performers” would agree that rotations longer than 3 or 4 days are detrimental to the overall health of engineering staff and therefore the entire system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;follow-the-sun&quot;&gt;Follow the Sun&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the sun shifts are nice for distributed teams. These allow for engineers to schedule their “on-call” shifts only during their normal working office hours. As they end their day and go home, engineers in a different time zone can take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course, there are many ways to customize shifts, especially for weekends when engineers need more flexibility. Engineers should be able to hand off the role to someone when personal conflicts arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/modules/incident-response-with-alerting-on-azure/&quot;&gt;MS Learn: Improve Incident Response with Alerting in Azure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-Remediation-Of-Incidents.html&quot;&gt;Remediation of Incidents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">A rotation is a scheduled shift. Engineers takes the “on-call” responsibility for their own specific recurring rotation. There are several types of shifts that you can create – some more common than others.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Determining What Incidents Are</title><link href="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Determining-What-Incidents-Are.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Determining What Incidents Are" /><published>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Determining-What-Incidents-Are</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Determining-What-Incidents-Are.html">&lt;p&gt;If you search online for “Incident Response” a majority of what you’ll find is information related to security threats and breaches. What doesn’t show up in the results is stuff about how to properly respond to threats related to something else entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How should a business respond to technical challenges and failures as they come up? The ones that affect reliability concerns such as availability, latency, correctness, and others. What happens when service level expectations are breached and it’s time for a human to get involved?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services such as VictorOps, PagerDuty, and others provide “on-call” solutions as well as documentation and best practices regarding this type of incident management. Service Now has opinions as well but the language is aimed more for those who follow ITSM guidance regarding service management. Ticketing with a tiered support structure doesn’t provide the fasted path to uptime for many companies however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the devops and web operations space, the idea of anyone but the engineers building the system responding to customer impacting problems is completely unacceptable. Irresponsible even. Time is of the essence and those who helped build the applications and underlying infrastructure are the best suited to maintain it’s health and upgrades in a production environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exactly when an engineer should be expected to take action is why we need to define what we mean by an incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can all agree that an incident is a “&lt;strong&gt;service disruption&lt;/strong&gt;” - something that is affecting our user’s ability to use the services they have come to rely on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a given. However, there are other things about incidents that are often overlooked or never considered. For example incidents are commonly subjective, feared, and unexpected&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;subjective&quot;&gt;Subjective&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you ask engineers across different organizations and industries, you will get many different answers about what an incident is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it is only when a customer is affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Others will label disruptions as incidents even if a customer never experienced a thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subjectivity is an unfortunate property of incidents in a lot of cases, even when it comes to identifying severity levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;feared&quot;&gt;Feared&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some cases, we downplay the significance of an outage … or worse … intentionally mis-label or not report a disruption in service for fear of reprimand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, we have felt that incidents reflected poorly in several areas of our engineering efforts and the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has not been until more recently through many of the conversations around devops and site reliability engineering, that we are starting to rethink incidents and now view them as opportunities to learn and improve our systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unexpected&quot;&gt;Unexpected&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words … unplanned Work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of what we as engineers and technologists do is planned work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spend a lot of time and effort understanding the work in front of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We calculate story points.  We plan sprints. We have a pretty good idea on what we are supposed to be working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when an incident occurs, it is disruptive. It is… unplanned work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, we view this as a terrible thing, but in reality, incidents are actually “investments” in supplying the value we are trying to deliver to end users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just need to change how we look at incidents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we’ll discuss the full lifecycle of an incident. From detection to analysis and everything in between. When we start to view incidents through a new lense and begin analyzing for opportunities to learn, you’ll begin to see your systems for what they are and why having a response plan in place makes sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/modules/incident-response-with-alerting-on-azure/&quot;&gt;MS Learn: Improve Incident Response with Alerting in Azure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-Understanding-the-Full-Lifecycle-of-an-Incident.html&quot;&gt;Understanding the Full Lifecycle of An Incident&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">If you search online for “Incident Response” a majority of what you’ll find is information related to security threats and breaches. What doesn’t show up in the results is stuff about how to properly respond to threats related to something else entirely.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Establishing Communication Channels</title><link href="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Establishing-Communications-Channel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Establishing Communication Channels" /><published>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Establishing-Communications-Channel</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Establishing-Communications-Channel.html">&lt;p&gt;To address some of the challenges around how we communicate we also want to find a way to create a unique channel or space for engineers to discuss the details of the incident - a “conversation bridge” in our persistent group chat tool -which for Tailwind Traders is Microsoft Teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want a channel that is unique to the incident only. We do not want conversations about other engineering efforts.We don’t want conversations about what people are doing for lunch. We ONLY want conversations related to the incident. Because then we can take that text (or data) and analyze later in a Post-incident review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using Logic App to create a workflow for responses (including Azure Boards, Azure Storage, Microsoft Teams)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Task: Using Logic Apps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-Communications-Channel.html&quot;&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-ChatOps.html&quot;&gt;Next&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">To address some of the challenges around how we communicate we also want to find a way to create a unique channel or space for engineers to discuss the details of the incident - a “conversation bridge” in our persistent group chat tool -which for Tailwind Traders is Microsoft Teams.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Establishing On-call Roles</title><link href="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Establishing-Oncall-Roles.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Establishing On-call Roles" /><published>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Establishing-Oncall-Roles</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Establishing-Oncall-Roles.html">&lt;p&gt;Creating a repeatable response plan means establishing who does what when something goes wrong. We don’t want there to be any question around who is supposed to be doing what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because of this, it is important to establish roles and the associated expectations. This isn’t a separation of duties exercise. In fact, we want to encourage less of that. It is however, a way of establishing better coordination and communication. It prevents people from stepping on each others toes while enabling cross-collaboration amongst not only on-call rosters, but an entire organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Primary Responder:&lt;/strong&gt; The first role we need to talk about is the “Primary Responder” – the Primary “On-call” engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This person is expected to acknowledge their awareness of an incident once the alert has been received.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secondary Responder:&lt;/strong&gt; Then we have the secondary responder – who is there as back up -Another engineer who can step in if the primary responder is unavailable or unreachable. Or if they just need another pair of eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incident Commander:&lt;/strong&gt; Another key role to identify, in many cases, is the incident commander. An incident commander can be extremely helpful when you have got a large-scale outage that effects a lot of different components or requires coordination across many teams and different systems. They are great for making sure that engineers stay focused and they are working on their own remediation efforts… Ensuring people are not stepping on each other or undoing each other’s work.  It is good to have a central person who can track what is going on and who is doing what.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication Coordinator:&lt;/strong&gt; The Communication Coordinator is meant to be the person working in conjunction with the incident commander to share more information beyond those who are in the firefight actively working to recover from the incident itself. That could be customers. It could be the sales and marketing teams. Maybe your customer support. There are many people within an organization who need to be made aware of what’s taking place and the status around how things are progressing. It’s always good to put someone in charge of managing that communication and making sure that other stakeholders are aware of what is happening and what’s being done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scribe:&lt;/strong&gt; The scribe’s role is to document the conversation in as much detail as possible. Teams commonly use phone bridges, conference calls, or video chat to get everyone together and try to understand what is going on, which can certainly help create space for the conversation. However, it is difficult for us to go through and understand in detail what the engineers were saying and doing unless it is transcribed. As a result, a scribe is that person who can help us document as much as possible to review later. What were people saying, doing, feeling, and even experiencing?  It is all data to be analyzed – but only if we capture it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject Matter Experts:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s quite common within on-call rosters to identify subject matter experts, so that early responders know who to escalate too quickly. These people should not be on call all the time, of course, but we do want to be able to identify who is our database expert. Who is our front-end expert? Who are the people that we can reach out to if our primary and secondary responders are not able to diagnose and resolve the issue themselves?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a closer look at each of these roles to better understand their place within our incident response efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/modules/incident-response-with-alerting-on-azure/&quot;&gt;MS Learn: Improve Incident Response with Alerting in Azure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-03-05-Primary-Responder.html&quot;&gt;The Primary Responder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Creating a repeatable response plan means establishing who does what when something goes wrong. We don’t want there to be any question around who is supposed to be doing what.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Managing Tasks from Group Chat - ChatOps</title><link href="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Managing-Tasks-from-Group-Chat-ChatOps.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Managing Tasks from Group Chat - ChatOps" /><published>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Managing-Tasks-from-Group-Chat-ChatOps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Managing-Tasks-from-Group-Chat-ChatOps.html">&lt;p&gt;Task: Webhook (started from Microsoft Teams) hits an Azure Function endpoint to update a static HTML (hypertext markup language) (status) page stored in Azure Storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-ChatOps.html&quot;&gt;Previous&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-Supplying-Context-And-Guidance.html&quot;&gt;Next&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Task: Webhook (started from Microsoft Teams) hits an Azure Function endpoint to update a static HTML (hypertext markup language) (status) page stored in Azure Storage.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Measuring Incident Response</title><link href="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Measuring-Incident-Response.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Measuring Incident Response" /><published>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Measuring-Incident-Response</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Measuring-Incident-Response.html">&lt;p&gt;The systems we work in eventually have problems. They are built, maintained, and supported by technolgists such as yourself. And when an issue inevitably occurs, someone needs to take action to restore services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many organizations don’t currently have an incident response plan in place. In fact, efforts to recover from service disruptions rarely follow any kind of repeatable and measured framework at all. Engineers react rather than respond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the increased reliance on digital services and their underlying technology it’s more important than ever to establish an explicit response plan. There are small steps that you could take immediately so that when the next problem occurs, everyone knows what to do. The incident itself can be viewed not just as an outage but an opportunity to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ttr&quot;&gt;TTR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you familiar with the acronym TTR?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is known as the “Time to Recover” or also sometimes referred to as the “time to remediate” or “time to restore.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, the total time that it takes for engineers to bring services back online… with regards to the value provided to end users and customers. It is the total duration of time for the incident?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The time to recover will vary from incident to incident and the circumstances around what contributed to the problem will rarely repeat. Because of this, measuring the TTR in aggregate can be a misleading metric. The Mean Time to Recover does not reflect a valuable performance metric on either the uptime of your systems or how well (or poorly) teams can respond to and remediate service disruptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not a perfect metric, it is one in which organizations can begin to measure how teams are performing when it comes to responding to incidents individually. We will need to examine the entire incident timeline to gain a broader understanding of what took place and where improvements can be made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most anyone who works with technology will agree that the complete prevention of problems is not very realistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, we must do better at knowing when something is wrong and being able to respond to it in an effective way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/modules/incident-response-with-alerting-on-azure/&quot;&gt;MS Learn: Improve Incident Response with Alerting in Azure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-Establishing-Oncall-Roles.html&quot;&gt;Establishing On-call Roles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The systems we work in eventually have problems. They are built, maintained, and supported by technolgists such as yourself. And when an issue inevitably occurs, someone needs to take action to restore services.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Remediation Of Incidents</title><link href="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Remediation-Of-Incidents.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Remediation Of Incidents" /><published>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Remediation-Of-Incidents</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Remediation-Of-Incidents.html">&lt;p&gt;Although thinking of incidents in terms of phases allows for us to shorten each in their own unique ways, responding to and remediating an incident often begin to blur. Especially when actions to mitigate or improve the situation, have the opposite result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve covered the foundations of building a good incident response plan, let’s talk about remediation efforts and what that looks like for Tailwind Traders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/modules/incident-response-with-alerting-on-azure/&quot;&gt;MS Learn: Improve Incident Response with Alerting in Azure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-Supplying-Context-And-Guidance.html&quot;&gt;Supplying Context &amp;amp; Guidance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Although thinking of incidents in terms of phases allows for us to shorten each in their own unique ways, responding to and remediating an incident often begin to blur. Especially when actions to mitigate or improve the situation, have the opposite result.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Supplying Context and Guidance</title><link href="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Supplying-Context-And-Guidance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Supplying Context and Guidance" /><published>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Supplying-Context-And-Guidance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Supplying-Context-And-Guidance.html">&lt;p&gt;Where to start? How on-call engineers should escalate incidents? What metrics, tools, links or general resources might be helpful? In a non-prescriptive way, what can be provided to help assist in the efforts to fix the problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/modules/incident-response-with-alerting-on-azure/&quot;&gt;MS Learn: Improve Incident Response with Alerting in Azure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-Updating-Stakeholders.html&quot;&gt;Update Stakeholders&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Where to start? How on-call engineers should escalate incidents? What metrics, tools, links or general resources might be helpful? In a non-prescriptive way, what can be provided to help assist in the efforts to fix the problems.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tracking Incident Details</title><link href="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Tracking-Incident-Details.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tracking Incident Details" /><published>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</published><updated>2020-03-05T12:40:12-06:00</updated><id>http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Tracking-Incident-Details</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://devopschampion.com/2020/03/05/2020-02-25-Tracking-Incident-Details.html">&lt;p&gt;Another thing we want to do, to address the challenges of Tailwind Traders and their incident response improvements is we want to be able to track:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-did-we-know-about-this-problem&quot;&gt;When Did We Know About This Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is this a new incident? If we are trying to reduce the time it takes to recover from incidents, we will need to start capturing when we are aware of issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only that but we want to keep track of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-we-know-about-the-problem&quot;&gt;How Did We Know About the Problem&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did our monitoring systems tell us, or did a customer inform us? If we plan to learn and improve, capturing how we knew will uncover improvement opportunities in our monitoring practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I am just finding out about a problem…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;am-i-the-first-to-know&quot;&gt;Am I the First to Know&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who else is aware?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And let us say others are aware of the problem…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-if-anything-is-being-done&quot;&gt;What (if anything) is Being Done&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is everyone assuming someone else is looking into it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-bad-is-it&quot;&gt;How Bad is It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We may not have any notion of severity or impact and there is no place for us to find out how bad the problem really is, and who is affected. These are tough questions to answer if nothing is tracked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/learn/modules/incident-response-with-alerting-on-azure/&quot;&gt;MS Learn: Improve Incident Response with Alerting in Azure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next-steps&quot;&gt;Next steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;2020-02-25-Measuring-Incident-Response.html&quot;&gt;Measuring Incident Response&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Another thing we want to do, to address the challenges of Tailwind Traders and their incident response improvements is we want to be able to track:</summary></entry></feed>